ORIGINAL WORK BY TATSUYA ENDO
SERIALIZED ON SHUEISHA'S SHONEN JUMP PLUS
MISSION 17: COMMENCE OPERATION GRIFFON
Good morning, Anya!
Good morning, Becky.
Did you see yesterday's Berlint in Love?
The couple finally reunited
after overcoming many obstacles.
That scene when Vincent hugged her
made my heart race.
Anya prefers to watch anime
instead of dramas.
Anya, you're still a child.
You seem uninterested in love.
I take back what I said
about you being mature.
Are you talking about being "lovey dovey"?
I guess this topic is
a little too advanced for Anya.
As long as there is love,
one can even fly in the sky.
Liar.
Heh. They're getting all excited about
stupid things this early in the morning.
Mid-term exams are coming up,
but I wonder if they're even studying.
Oh! It's the second son.
Here's a summary of what happened
previously.
The second son could not understand
Bond's charm,
so Anya failed the Friendship Strategy.
If you can give your dog a cool name,
I'll invite you to my house as a reward.
Can Anya overcome
the second son's bullying
to accomplish her mission?
Anya's battle will continue on.
Thanks for watching.
And so, Anya has brought
a secret weapon today.
Yesterday I asked Father
to let me take a family portrait
with Bond.
If I show this to him…
Whoa! What's with this big dog?
Let's see if he's stronger than my dog!
I'm sorry I ignored you the other day!
His name is Bond.
Oopsie! I accidentally dropped
the picture of
Anya's cool dog. Oh, how careless of me.
The exam covers so many areas.
Yes, that's right…
Oh no!
Come on, who cares about them?
What's attractive is not kids like them,
but someone with sophisticated charm.
Hey Anya, you dropped something.
He's so handsome.
Who is this incredibly handsome man?
Is this your father, Anya?
How come you never told me about this?
Introduce him to me!
Hey, what's his name?
Is he going out with anyone?
Wh… what?! Father is married to Mother!
Can I have this picture?
Thank you!
Give it back to me! I have to show it
to the second son!
They're so loud.
He's so handsome.
It's time for your arts and crafts class,
but Professor Rodin is out sick.
So I will be your substitute.
Your assignment today
is to use the materials here
to make a three dimensional object.
The theme is animals.
I'll randomly divide everybody
into groups.
Materials given to each group
will be limited in number,
so use it wisely by communicating
with your group members.
Yes, sir.
Group one. Herman Clark.
This class will be so much fun.
-What are you going to make?
-Well--
This is child's play. How boring.
You're absolutely right.
I heard from someone in class two that
the higher-ups of this school will be
coming to look at the finished artwork.
What?
It might affect our evaluation report.
I guess it's worth putting in an effort.
Hey guys. Don't cause me trouble
if we're put in the same group.
What?
Next is group four.
Damian Desmond, Anya Forger…
This is my chance!
I had a feeling this would happen!
Hey you! You better not bother me!
Anya, we couldn't be
in the same group, huh?
Oh yeah, give me back my picture.
I have to show it to the second son.
Why?
You said that I can have it!
-I never said that!
-Do you have any other pictures?
-Give it back!
-Get back to your seats!
Now that it has come to this,
I'll use these materials
and make a cool looking Bond
to impress the second son!
You may begin!
I'm going to make a rabbit!
-Me too!
-Do we have enough paper?
Can I borrow that pen after you?
The quality and expressiveness
of the work they create
while using a limited amount of materials,
will of course be part of the evaluation.
But what we must take
particular note of, is the process.
The existence or non-existence
of cooperativeness,
flexibility, assertiveness,
and originality.
Becky Blackbell. What is that?
It's Anya's father!
Loid Forger?! That's too original!
Not only that,
I will add on the combat suit
that my family's company is developing…
As a dress-up item!
I admit that the motif is elegant,
but I told you that the theme
is "animals"! Start over again.
Teacher…
In the end, humans are animals too.
Whoa! That is true!
Touché. I give you permission
to continue, Blackbell…
Oh, but Mr. Loid is probably
super intellectual,
so it would be rude to call him an animal.
I'll remake this!
Whoa.
It's complete!
Huh?
His name is Bond.
You have a tendency to name your trash?
Operation Dog has come to an end.
What operation?
And that was supposed to be a dog?
What are you making, Damian?
Hm?
A griffin, which is also included
in our family crest.
Just as I expected of you, Damian!
What a unique idea!
Griffin? Is he related to Chimera?
I plan to use a lot of paper,
so you guys better not use much.
What?
Sure thing!
Since I'm using my family crest,
I can't mess up.
That's right! If I can make this into
an amazing piece of art…
Father, please take a look at this.
I made the Desmond family griffin.
This is rather impressive.
It perfectly expresses our family's
dignity and elegance.
Damian, you're the pride of
the Desmond family.
That's my goal.
Second son, Anya will help you
make the griffin!
Are you serious? You're so nice!
Thank you!
Look at this, Father!
Isn't this an amazing griffin?
Anya made half of it!
Wow. Anya, you've got
an incredible talent!
I'd love to meet the parents that
raised you! Bring them here.
Mission complete.
I'll go with Operation Griffin,
instead of Operation Dog. This'll work!
Huh?
Will I have enough time and materials
to make this?
The wings will be a hassle.
-Second son.
-Huh?
Anya will help you make that.
You can use Anya's paper too.
Huh? What are you saying?
Make your own project!
It's already finished.
You're planning to turn this in?
Are you serious?
Anya wants to help you.
Do whatever you want!
Okay.
Oh, I see! I finally understand now, Anya.
I was wondering why she was
so concerned about him.
All right then,
can you make the hind legs?
Okey dokey.
Oh? Are they planning to make
one project by working together?
This is very interesting,
Forger and Desmond.
I did it!
Huh? What is that? I told you to make
the hind legs, didn't I?
I attached a jet engine so that it can
fly with lots of power!
Stop adding weird things on your own.
-Forget it! Just make the wings!
-Leave it up to me!
Ta-da!
What do you mean, "Ta-da"?
It's sloppy and uneven! You think it can
fly with this piddly amount of wings?
Don't worry.
It can fly with the jet engine.
I won't use that!
Stay out of this!
All you did was waste paper!
You're useless!
Oh no!
Damian, you're being too harsh.
Shut up! Hand over your paper!
I cannot overlook this conduct any longer!
This is not elegant!
Desmond, can you say that you're behaving
like a gentleman?
But… Damn it. It's over for me.
I can't complete this thanks
to this shorty.
I was planning to show this to Father…
No need to rush, Desmond.
Do all that you can with your
current abilities.
That's not good enough.
Time's up. Place your work in the hallway.
-Look at this!
-Your giraffe has short legs.
Well, what's wrong with your lion's mane?
My work is the best.
Second son, I'm sorry that
I was so useless.
I'll give you this in place of the wings.
What is that?
Isn't it the garbage that you made?
I reconstructed it into a female griffin.
Make it a set with your griffin.
Huh?
Why do I have to pair it up with mine?
I heard that one can even fly in the sky,
as long as there is love.
What?
I see. Are these the arts and crafts
projects by the first graders?
They are all so cute.
Oh?
This is…
What?
That artwork won first prize?
The higher-ups from the Board of Education
took a real liking to it.
The griffin was standing valiantly
despite its wings being ripped apart,
and that reminded them of our country's
future recovery from war.
What? Oh, I see…
From that piece of garbage?
-You're amazing, Damian.
-Just as I expected.
Above all, they could not hold back
their tears at the sight
of the shockingly pitiful looking
small griffin placed on the side.
Good for you, second son. You can proudly
tell your parents about this.
It's according to plan.
Huh? Why would I show my parents
that embarrassing
piece of artwork?
Oh no!
Operation Griffin has come to an end.
Hello? Hi, Jeeves, it's me.
Yeah, everything is good.
Is Max doing well?
Yes. Will you be coming home
during your next break?
Well, Father won't be home anyways, right?
Yes, you're right.
But Demetrius will be coming home
during the break.
The exam is coming up,
so I'll stay here and concentrate
on studying.
I thought you'd say that, Damian.
Oh yeah, today for
the arts and crafts assignment…
Never mind, it's nothing.
Jeeves, you told Father
about what happened during
the entrance ceremony, right?
Did he say anything about that?
Yes, he sure did.
He was very worried about your welfare.
Liar.
I see. Thanks. I'll be going now.
Father is not interested in me.
-That was a coincidence…
-Ewen, Emile.
-Hey, Damian.
-You're finished with your call?
Yeah. Let's practice for the test
with our teacher after we eat.
Of course!
Let's focus on language arts
since it's Damian's weak point.
Shut up.
I have no choice
but to become an Imperial Scholar!
First prize.
First prize…
Sylvia Sherwood.
Handler for the Westalian Intelligence
Services' Eastern-Focused Division, WISE.
XX years old, and single.
On the surface, she works at
the Westalis embassy in the East
as a diplomat,
and under the surface,
she commands a few secret agents
while evading strict surveillance
by the Secret Police.
Because of her thoroughly guarded
imposing figure,
other workers named her
"Fullmetal Lady," and they were all
in fear of her.
MISSION 17: FULLMETAL LADY
We will now begin tailing
secretary Sherwood of Westalis.
I guess they never know when to quit.
Same clothes, same shop,
and same route.
Every Wednesday,
I go to the public pool.
Once they're aware of
Sylvia's regular routine,
the wheels in their lazy brain
will stop turning.
It's her usual pool time.
She won't come out for at least an hour.
Should we go eat?
As long as I can create some down time,
it's not difficult to
move freely, even within enemy territory.
All right, I guess I'll head out to
meet up with Twilight.
And then he tripped.
What an idiot.
This coat I just purchased is not so bad.
Any fool that lets their guard down
can't survive in this world.
Hello. Or should I say good evening,
Agent Twilight.
…And that's the summary of
the income report from the Desmond camp.
One of them is a paper company
and although there are only
a few publicized numbers…
I can't say it.
How can I say, "Your brand new coat
still has a tag attached to it."?
No, I can't.
There's no way I can say that to Handler,
the Fullmetal Lady.
Loid Forger. The codename is Twilight.
He is a member of WISE,
who completes his missions tirelessly
for the sake of peace.
He is a solitary spy who has left behind
an ordinary life of happiness.
Meeting up with Handler is always
a life or death situation.
When Handler is being followed,
we must discreetly throw them
off the scent.
Two towards the north
and one towards the east, huh?
Should we cancel it?
No, let's meet up at point C.
We'll make it quick.
Roger.
That's how, daily we exchange
confidential information for the sake
of peace between the East and West.
Hello. Or should I say good evening,
Agent Twilight.
Report on the progress of Operation Strix.
My daughter…
can now jump a level higher
on the vaulting box.
And as for jump roping,
she can jump five times consecutively.
What the hell is he talking about?
MISSION 17: OMELETTE RICE
Yuri! I tried cooking something!
Here's an omelet with rice.
Wow, Sis, you're amazing!
I wonder what this object is.
Thank you for the food!
PLEASE WAIT FOR A MOMENT
Sis, it's delicious! Ugh!
I'm so glad!
I'll try to serve homemade meals
from now on.
I tried making cream pasta.
Wow! I can't see the shape of
the pasta at all! How amazing!
Ta-da! It's a cake!
Wow! I've never seen such a blue cake
before in my life! How amazing!
Sis, if you're this good at cooking,
you can get married in no time!
Oh Yuri, you're making me blush.
The man grew up to be
physically strong and tough.
You were feeling dizzy after pulling
an all-nighter for four days,
and got hit by a truck yesterday,
didn't you? Be more careful.
There's nothing to worry about.
MISSION 18:
THE HOME TUTOR UNCLE/DAYBREAK
Subtitle translation by: Lili Morita